Okay, so lesson five is schedule
management, right, and so these are some
of the objectives and some of the learning
objectives for schedule management.
Now, schedule management itself is a huge
topic, it's a big, big topic, and that's
why we have divided schedule management
into two lessons.
So this is part one, and then we also have
Lesson 6, which is Schedule Management,
part two.
So part one really just introduces the
concepts of scheduling, right,
the concept of schedule management.
So you need to understand what schedule
management appreciate the value of
schedule management, right, why that's
important on your project.
You also need to understand the difference
between the two approaches, right,
predictive approach and the agile approach
to schedule management.
There are two very, very different
approaches to manage in the schedule.
And so you, You need to understand the
difference between the two.
We'll also talk about terms such as
dependencies and relationships.
You need to understand what the difference
is between the two.
We'll talk about leads and lags along
those same lines as well.
Plus, we're going to be talking about
different estimating methods.
There's different ways of estimating your
schedule based on whether it's an
iterative process or whether it's an agile
process.
So you need to understand the different
estimating methods, Also, different
prioritisation techniques, how we're going
to prioritize all of our different
activities, right, to basically then
develop our schedule.
Again, prioritization generally is more of
an agile approach.
So, again, you need to understand that the
difference between the agile approach and
the predictive approach to schedule
management.
And then you need to understand then all
the documents, the artifacts, and the
tools and techniques
that we're going to be
covering in the schedule
management section.